[Music]
i know you all realize the problems
associated with being dehydrated
and so you may be thinking to yourself i
need to start drinking more water
that'll solve my hydration problems
well maybe but that could also lead to
what we call hyper hydration
and so you don't want to just drink more
water you want to find out how to
actually
optimize your hydration status right so
looking at an online calculator that
tells you how much water to drink
throughout the day
no right we can do better than that
that's not what it takes to be optimally
hydrated
all right so what i want to present to
you in this condensed version
is how to develop individualized
hydration plans to help you optimize
your performance
now i have recently filmed a couple of
mega episodes on this topic
several hours worth right but in this
version i'm going to skip
to the very basics and get just to the
practical application portion so what to
do and how to do it
okay if you want to know more about the
physiology how it's working
more recent research specific numbers i
would encourage you to go check out that
two-part 55-minute physiology series
but if you're just here for the what to
do and how to do it i welcome you and
let's jump into this episode of
25-minute physiology
all right so i'm titleist this talk the
three steps to optimizing hydration so
i'll break this thing down to you in
three steps okay so our solution is
really a function of
first and foremost making sure you start
in a you hydrated state and i'll talk
about what that is then you have to
prevent what we call hypo hydration
as a result of either exercise or work
and then you have to
part three or step three is fully
replenish the fluids you lost during
that exercise or work session
okay so let's go from the beginning one
two and three and i'll show you exactly
what they mean how to do it and what
numbers you want to hit
let's roll all right now part of number
two is
relying on part number one right so the
best way to stay
optimally hydrated during your workouts
is to start hydrated in the first place
and then likewise the only way to
continue you hydration is to make sure
that you replenish the stuff from
exercise so
really it's three parts but it's it's
all one
circular system if you will another way
to think about this i guess more
simplistically is
how much and what to drink during the
day during your workouts
and after so let's get started with step
number one which is starting
you hydrated now again you may have
heard things like
oh drink a gallon of water a day or
eight glasses or maybe more specifically
half your body weight this would be in
pounds in ounces per water so if you
weigh 200 pounds
half your body weight is 100 pounds so
drink 100 ounces
of water not 100 pounds of water and
that's a lot better of course right the
difference between that last one that
one in yellow and the first two is at
least it's relative
to your body size so we don't have 125
pound person trying to drink the same
amount of
water as a 300 pound person that doesn't
make any sense so if you want to just
head your bets and start there
that's a lot better than just drinking a
certain number of
glasses of water per day
but you do need to take into context
what your day looks like
so i'm not going to go into the details
you can stop the video and look at this
the result of this study here but the
point is you need to consider
really two functions one how hot and
humid it is
where you're working and then two how
much you're working the day so you could
be as little as
say two liters about a half a gallon a
day or you could be as high as 10
liters right so five times that amount
and that needs to be adjusted based on
both the temperature
and the work so start with that half uh
thing i just showed you half body weight
pronounces
and then scale up or down based on the
oops at least scale up based on the
humidity and the amount of work you do
okay so we also have to consider our
diet so
where our water comes from in our life
about fifty percent of it comes from
just you know drinking water
exogenously what we'll call it thirty
percent comes from other fluids coffee
tea etc
and about twenty percent comes from our
food but
this last twenty percent we know is
wildly different between people so
depending on your diet
that number may be 30 maybe 10 percent
or could be i guess significantly even
different from that so most fruits and
vegetables are 85
or higher in terms of water content
right meaning if you're eating a diet
full of these things you're actually
getting a lot of water just in your food
even products like eggs and meat are
still actually
mostly water and so eating a diet
composed of things like this is going to
get you a lot of water content
eating a diet composed of things like
this and i'm not against biscuits
but they're incredibly dense okay so
what we know is highly processed foods
have lower water content a lot of times
because they've been baked or cooked or
fried
out as well as excessively high salt
intake now we don't mind salt in fact
we're going to go out of our way to get
salt
i'll talk about that a little bit but
these things come pretty excessively
right so if you need to get say four
grams of salt in today
you could probably easily get that or
more in one meal
of things like this and if you have two
or three meals like this you're actually
getting
way too high salt content this is
particularly problematic for people who
are overweight and physically inactive
if you're an active person salt's a good
thing right but it's always about
context and amount
point being if you have a diet like this
again water sparse foods and highly
processed
meaning highly salted that 20 may go
down to
say 10 and so what you actually have to
do then is go significantly
up in the amount of water you go out of
your way to get so in this case you may
have to go up to three quarters
uh your body weight in ounces per day to
hit those official numbers okay
or the other solutions to have to sit
around drinking so much water is just to
eat more real whole fresh food
okay so then rather than relying on a
stupid generic number i actually
recommend that you measure and see
and so this is how you should do it
first thing when you wake up or as close
to it
you should actually measure your
hydration and one way to do it if you're
a super nerd is you could buy things
like this
now these are not that expensive i guess
that expensive
is sort of relative but you can measure
hydration kits there's all kinds of ways
to do it i've used this one specifically
so my athletes we have these in our
laboratory and they're not that
expensive and you can measure your
hydration status
or you can buy certain scales now a lot
of these things commercially available
not even that expensive will actually
tell you your body weight
body percentage as well as your
hydration level now they're not
perfectly accurate but they're probably
fairly reliable so you can use them day
in and day out at least you would notice
major changes in your hydration status
if that's still too rich for your blood
you can use an even simpler system which
is a combination of two things
one how thirsty you feel in the morning
call it a scale of one to ten
jot it down as well as the color of your
urine i like to combine both of these
things so you're not
kind of thrown off for example if you're
just breathing a lot through your mouth
overnight you may
feel like a dry mouth and you may feel
thirsty you're not actually that you
just have a dry mouth because you're not
breathing through your nose properly at
night
so i like to combine them both okay and
you can look at this chart here or many
others
regarding how what the color of your
urine should be
and i'll give you a hand it shouldn't be
crystal clear now that that's bad for
you but you're probably drinking too
much
pure water if you're peeing out you know
a diamond colored urine it should have a
light tinge to it for the most part
okay so
to recap part number one starting your
day and being just you hydrated
throughout the day
start by drinking you know that amount
of water like we talked about measure
your hydration status
with those whichever method i just
explained to you and then adjust the
amount of water you're drinking
throughout the day based on your diet
lifestyle
and various other environmental factors
so let's move on to step number two
preventing exercise induced or work
induced
or competition induced hypohydration
well this is a really big deal for
performance in fact we see that
being dehydrated by as little as one to
two percent
can have significant reductions in your
physical performance or your ability now
when i say one to two percent what i
mean is
you've lost that percentage of body
weight so again let's imagine you are
200 pounds
and you've lost one percent that would
be two pounds of water okay so that's
how we determine percent
that's not percent dehydration is
percent of body weight loss
nonetheless so you can see people out to
here right imagine you got somewhere in
the neighborhood of two to two and a
half percent
dehydrated which you wouldn't feel that
awful right honestly
that probably happens with hanging out
in the jacuzzi one night
you could lose that amount with really
even feeling it well your exercise
capacity is already down 10
well if you're a performance athlete
either in competition or in training
losing 10 right off the gates is i mean
that's it that's the difference between
making the team and being an all-star
you've got a job or you don't right it's
a big big big deal
so an example i could give you here is
imagine 185 pound athlete
you can see that losing two pounds would
be a one percent reduction and again you
wouldn't even feel that necessarily
most sweat weights are somewhere between
one to five pounds per
hour and most of the athletes i've ever
worked with are at least
three or higher six pounds plus is not
that crazy for
this size of an athlete and so it's not
very difficult at all to lose three four
five pounds in an hour
if you're not drinking any water back
all right so that becomes a real problem
the other thing that we know that
happens is slight reductions in
hydration status have pretty large
increases in perceptual strain
in other words you may be performing at
the same level but it feels a lot harder
and i don't have to explain to you why
that sucks
all right moreover
several studies have shown things like
even slight reductions in hydration
can influence skill things like accuracy
for example this study showed that
basketball players had a progressive
deterioration and performance in both
time and accuracy of shooting
as their dehydration progressed from one
to two to three to four percent they
continually got worse worse and more
source
so stopping yourself for that one
percent or going from two to three
even that little very that little amount
right there can you know
be the difference between competition
right
so how much do you drink during this
game or competition or workout
well it is individualized and i would
encourage you to check out this really
nice article i believe it's open and
free access so you can google the title
and go read it
and they lay out the fact that there's a
lot of different things going into
how much you need to drink so the exact
solution depends on all these factors
like
air flow what clothing you're wearing
male or female
how big you are the length of the
session the altitude etc okay
but the point is it requires
individualization so
as i was mentioning some typical sweat
rates are between one to five pounds per
hour or so and that depends on body size
exercise intensity duration your
pre-hydration status
in other words if you start off
dehydrated you don't sweat as much if
you're over hydrated you'll sweat more
and the heat and humidity these are the
five big categories that i pay attention
to
and i will kind of just scale up or down
depending on how these things are
modified once i know the baseline
or normal sweat rate of the individuals
and so i'll give you kind of
a cheating method for how much water to
drink right now
what the research will typically say is
we want to go for 2 milliliters of water
per kilogram of body weight per 15
minutes or so
an easy way to get to that my cheating
method is just take their body weight in
pounds and divide it by 30.
okay so you can see the example here
that 185 pound athlete
divided by 30 would be six okay that
would be roughly equivalent to
the other method the two by kilograms a
minute
which would give you 5.6 the difference
between 5.6 ounces and 6 ounces
it's the same exact thing when it comes
to actually doing this in real life
so i think my method of divide by 30 is
pretty good
and you would drink that every 15
minutes now i know you don't know what
ounces really are
are you not familiar with those numbers
and so i've said okay
imagine this you know an aquafina bottle
or something that you get
at the grocery store they're usually in
16 or 20 ounce bottles just take a look
if it's a 20 ounce bottle you need to
get somewhere between 5 and 6 ounces in
you know you're going to drink a quarter
of that plus or minus okay that's
probably pretty close from most of us
in fact if you just wanted to give
everyone like five or six ounces every
15 minutes regardless of size
it's probably pretty close okay
you do want to give them prescriptions
and you want to give them numbers and
you want to give them markers to hit
though because we know very clearly from
the research
that first during exercise is a very
poor indicator
of how much water to drink now outside
of exercise like checking it first thing
in the morning it's actually pretty okay
but given to the left their own accord
we know that people will drink only
about half the fluids that they need
on their own volition right especially
in the cold right so you can see this
athlete here making a pretty poor
hydration choice
uh during her hiking workout naughty
tatiana
right so four tricks or four tips that
you can do to help people
or your athletes drink more water number
one make sure it's the right temperature
so people tend to like cool water but
not extremely cold
give it some flavor add some salt and
then make sure it's visible in other
words make sure it's in their line of
sight so
don't put it in the corner way behind
the bleachers make sure that they every
between every rep and drill they see
water and that's going to remind them oh
yeah drink my fluids drink my fluid
so when you do those four things the
amount of involve or amount of voluntary
fluid intake
goes up significantly so that's
something that can really really help
you and if it's again you yourself make
sure your water bottle is right there in
front of your squat rack
or off to the corner don't hide it in
the corner or buried off uh
in the corner of the gym somewhere okay
so now we understand a lot a little bit
more about how much to drink during our
workouts what should actually
be in the drink i just mentioned we want
some flavor and some salt but how much
let's talk about it we know that the
answer is not just straight water
partially because of what i just told
you if you give them to straight water
they don't drink enough
but also because if we think about it
this way the problem is you're sweating
right
you're not sweating water you're
sweating sweat so you don't want to
drink back water you want to drink back
sweat
so we have to take a second to look at
what are the actual contents in sweat
right well we know it's primarily this
sodium chloride potassium and glucose
are the things you mostly lose during
exercise
now you maybe lose a tiny bit of
magnesium but it's not a significant
player
and all this the vast majority of it's
going to be the sodium and chloride
in fact it's about a four to one ratio
of sodium and chloride
to potassium right so if you lose a gram
of sodium you probably lose like 250
milligrams
of potassium a gram of sodium would also
probably mean a gram of chloride
plus or minus right so
we want to drink back a fluid that is
the exact same concentration as the
concentration
in our cells so we have most of our
fluid is in our cell
in between our cells which is called the
interstitial space or in our plasma one
of those three
areas okay if we drink back things that
are too dilute say just water
this the part in between the cells and
the blood gets really expanded
but it's also incredibly dilute so that
does not enough time for your body to
pull the water into the cell from there
so you actually end up peeing
out a lot of the fluid so too dilute
means you waste a lot of fluids you're
not optimally actually rehydrating
you're putting water in your body
and then you're peeing it right back out
you're also then turning off your thirst
sensors so you don't think you have to
drink as more because you're not as
thirsty
until you start peeing clear and you're
thinking you're hydrated when you're
actually not
the inverse if you drink something too
concentrated so too salty too much
electrolyte in it
you can actually pull fluid into your
intestines
right so this fluid you drink goes in
your gut it should then
go into your plasma but it has to go
through a little bit of digestion and
when it does that since it's so
concentrated it pulls water from the
plasma in there
osmosis right we want to balance both
sides here and when you pull a bunch of
water into your intestines
you know what happens right so too
dilute you pee too much and you're not
hydrated
too concentrated you get diarrhea so we
want to avoid
those situations entirely and we can do
that by understanding truly what is in
our sweat
and so on average if you were to lose
one liter of sweat which would be
a fairly normal number 2.2 pounds let's
say in an hour
again this would be average average to
maybe even a little bit low of a sweat
rate
what would be in that one liter probably
something like
anywhere between 500 to 2000 milligrams
2 000 milligrams is also 2 grams
right 1 to 500 milligrams of potassium
and that kind of 4 1 ratio like i
mentioned
and as i said sodium and chloride seem
to be
pretty well linked here there are some
small amounts
of magnesium but also keep in mind even
though it's a
it's a tiny amount if you do start
sweating a lot
a tiny relative amount magnified over a
high absolute volume
ends up being a decent amount right so
even though say you're you're sweating
out 50 milligrams of
magnesium per liter well if you sweat
out five liters
that number actually goes from 50
milligrams to 250 milligrams which is
how i'm actually now actually a
significant amount
okay so i actually don't mind putting a
little bit of magnesium back in
as a result of sweat if the sweat volume
is a lot
okay now within this one thing you can
do is try to figure out
all right am i closer that 500
milligrams
of sodium chloride or that 2000 that's a
big difference
well you can invest in a number of
different things that you can purchase
that have sweat patches you put the
sweat patch on and it tells you the
amount the rate as well as more
importantly
the sodium and chloride and potassium
and like i said typically once you know
the sodium number you can
guesstimate the chlorides the same
although it's not always true
and then the potassium's the other way
so you can look around the internet and
buy
any number of those there you can also
just kind of look at your clothing
so if your clothing is covered in white
afterwards so once your shirt and hat
dry
then you know you have a pretty high
salt content if it's low then it's
if it's if it's clear though and there's
not a lot of salt residue then you don't
sweat a lot of salt
most people i'd say the average is a
thousand milligrams of
sodium that would be kind of like a a
light sweater uh really heavy folks or
maybe 1500
so those are pretty good range if you
don't know start with a thousand
milligrams
started at 250 milligrams of potassium
and then a thousand
or so of chloride all right
so that's what i would recommend now
let's say that you went through an
actual workout with this
individual and i gave you the kind of
relative concentration per liter but
maybe you went through a workout and you
lost two actual liters so we double
these amounts this is what you would
look like
in terms of most likely sweating but we
also have to account the fact that when
you did a two hour workout or an hour
workout
then you've burned some glucose this is
critically important because again
we wanna drink sweat and sweat you don't
sweat out glucose but you burn glucose
as a part of physical activity so
they're highly associated so we got to
bring this back in the equation
as well okay so what we want to do is
this
i know that if we bring in and just add
some salt to our water we'll take care
of that chloride
and sodium issue but we haven't hit
potassium we haven't had magnesium
and we're missing our sugar content okay
so we got to do more than just that
now if we took a look at different uh
hydration products this is what we're
looking at
now i've done this in terms of amount
per 2 liters
all right because i'm giving you a
specific example you can imagine in 2
liters
this is exactly how much you lost so you
can look over here with what we
calculated as what we lost and over here
to what the same amount of fluid
would give us and you can see pretty
clearly that things like powerade and
gatorade
if we lost in this middle range say two
grams of
sodium and two grams of chloride
and we lost two liters of fluid if we
drink back two flu
two liters of powerade or gatorade we're
not even getting half
of the amount back of sodium we need so
the problem with these
sports drinks is they typically don't
have nearly enough salt they also don't
have any magnesium
they're low on potassium and they're
okay in terms of the
they're good in terms of the amount of
sugar but it's also the wrong type of
sugar
right it's not not optimal is what i'll
say so can they work
sure but are they optimal no when we go
on to one of the next most popular ones
pedialyte
we see that it has a really high
potassium concentration and the sodium
is actually pretty good
but probably too low of carbs and not
enough magnesium
the other thing i don't like about these
general drinks is you really can't
influence content
or concentration so these can't be
individualized
right so in fact i like other things
which are specific hydration products
right having said that if you're also
like hey i don't like processed things i
just want to have stuff that's all
natural
two other really popular items
are coconut water and actually
surprising enough milk
and the beauty of coconut water is it is
extremely high in potassium but it's not
high enough in sodium it's got good and
the right types of carbohydrates
so if you're going to use coconut water
you're going to have to come back and
add a lot of salt to it
and then maybe even a little bit of
carbohydrate but that's a very viable
option
the other one that folks don't think
about a lot is actually milk which is
pretty damn good for the most part
you're gonna have to add some salt to it
but the nice part about it is it's an
excellent potassium source
it's got a good amount of magnesium and
the sugar is almost ideal
so you're there okay the other way that
i go
to be honest with you i don't know a lot
of folks who like to drink milk during
their workouts so milk really is more of
a recovery hydration product than it is
in workout one and so my preferred
option is actually to use
hydration packets now these aren't
relative to
two liters so these are single packets
and they're typically
you're typically told to dilute them in
16 ounces of water
so if you actually did that and you
scaled that and you multiplied that by
four
you would actually multiply that by four
and so the amount of say sodium you
would get in the satellite 70
would be more like 1400 milligrams which
is a lot closer to that 2
000 milligrams number and a lot higher
than this
so these are actually pretty good you
can see that um the three kind of most
classic ones
serolite new and drip drop are usually
in about two to one potassium
sodium to potassium ratios i think it
should be a little bit higher sodium
personally
sarah lights doesn't have any magnesium
noon does but it doesn't have any
carbohydrates which is fine
they're typically not trying to give you
the carbohydrates anyways
so you can use them and again the thing
i like about them the most is it allows
you to individualize so
if you wanted someone say in a 16 ounce
water to have a little bit more sodium
or something
or a little bit more total or a little
bit less you can put in a half a packet
or three quarters or pack it in half
or whatever also companies like
sterilite make multiple kinds so this is
cellulite 70 they make cellulite 90
which is more sodium concentrated
so they actually make different
concentrations for you which is really
nice
and then of course there's also a new
company element which actually has
closer to that five to one ratio which i
think is a little bit better
a good amount of magnesium but is
missing the carbohydrate okay
so you can use any of these or any
combinations of these
for example you could take a little bit
of element and put that in your coconut
water
and boy you're off to a good start or or
whatever else you want to do okay
you can also then titrate these so for
example if you're just in a situation
where you're sweating but you're not
actually working out a lot then maybe
you do go to one of these packs that are
a little bit lower in sugar
and not something like coconut water
because you don't need as much
carbohydrate back you mainly need the
salt and water
up to you right depending on your
situation
so the best way though to fix all this
stuff in reality is
trial and error you're going to have to
figure out what works best for you and
your athlete what
feels best in their stomach and what
they like the taste of etc
but to summarize all of point number two
what to drink during your workouts
that same amount of water we talked
about body weight divided by 30 every 15
minutes or so somewhere between a 3
or 4 2 1 sodium chloride to potassium
ratio
maybe even some magnesium a 5 to 9 or so
percent concentration of mainly glucose
and some fructose
and then practice a bunch right the
other thing you want to do is make sure
this fluid is within eyesight so make
sure your individuals conceive if you do
this you'll have ticked up all the
things they'll see it they'll drink more
it'll taste good right temperature it'll
have some salt and you'll be off your
way
okay now the problem with this is
if you do some basic calculations here
and you use our cheating method
and you said okay let's take that six
ounces
and we drink it every 15 minutes so
that's four times per hour
that would give us 24 ounces or about
one and a half pounds per hour
unfortunately as you may or
be picking up on that's not enough total
fluid right most people sweat
at minimum 1.5 pounds per hour a lot
up to three four five pounds so in the
case of of a professional boxer mike lee
over here
five pounds an hour is not crazy to him
if he followed this number i told you
he would still be three and a half
pounds short
well the problem was saying okay well
why don't you just drink more why don't
you go like
you know 10 ounces per 15 minutes or
something
well that becomes a problem because of
what's called gastric emptying so
there's only so much fluid you can have
in your stomach and get out
and depending on what sport you're in
say soccer you don't have the ability to
drink during the game
it's not an option boxing is very
difficult right you only get one more
round there's only so much you can get
in
and so it's really not just very
feasible to get more in during your
workout
what's our solution then well number one
you have to start pre-hydrated
and then you have to recover things
which is step number three
replenishing post exercise okay
so my recommendation for doing this
first of all you have to you have to
measure and you have to figure out how
much am i losing
right again you can use these laboratory
methods that i talked about you can
measure your hydration status before and
after
the workout or you can simply take your
body weight so get naked completely dry
weigh yourself do your workout get
completely dry naked
weigh yourself again if you lost five
pounds in your workout
and you didn't drink any water then you
know exactly what you weighed okay
now when you do this method don't forget
to account for the water you drink
so in other words you were 170 before
you finished your workout now you're 165
but you drank a pound and a half of
water
well then you didn't lose 5 pounds in
that workout 170 to 165 you actually
lost
six and a half pounds because you drank
a pound and a half back already
but then nonetheless let's just say um
you were following my thing and i said
okay great and you drink one and a half
pounds of water during the workout and
you weighed in pre you weighed in post
five pound difference you drink your one
pound one pound half water
so you still know that you're short
three and a half pounds
well if you go and then drink three and
a half pounds of fluid it's not going to
work
because we know you're actually going to
urinate that out so you have to actually
drink more than that in fact we're going
to recommend drinking somewhere between
to 150 of that number
so if you needed to actually gain back
three and a half pounds you actually
need to drink more like five pounds
because some of that's going to be lost
in urine especially if you drink
something that's too dilute
all right so to summarize your
post-workout
figuring out how much to drink you can
use what's called the what
method and you can see the article that
i got it from here bob kenofick is a
legendary
hydration scientist from the army and he
basically said okay
take your weight look at your urine
color and your thirst
w-u-t you combine that together and if
you've got
more than two say for example you're
you've lost weight
from the workout and your urine is
discolored or
you've lost weight and you're thirsty or
the other combination
then it's very likely you're dehydrated
okay if you have all three you're
thirsty your waist down and your urine's
discolored
you basically just bank on it the fact
that you are dehydrated
okay so post exercise fluids you should
consume about 125 to 150
of the fluid that was lost during
exercise and what do you drink drink
that exact combination of sweat that we
just got done covering
in part two okay so to summarize this
entire video here and to give some
specific recommendations
the first thing i think you should do in
the morning is to wake up and do some
assessment of your hydration status and
then from there i personally like just
chugging some water i will fill up a
glass like this
top to brim it's right next to my bed i
wake up in the morning do whatever
not much and the first thing i do would
be
i hope you heard the sound of that on
the mic but i will finish that entire
thing
right just to get myself going on the
right track
okay so wake up and chug a little bit of
water as you first start going
then i eat a diet that is mostly whole
real fresh foods especially fruits and
vegetables and i salt them liberally
okay a lot of salt on that stuff
especially when i'm training more
if you're eating more processed and
packaged foods you don't need to go out
of your way in fact you probably
shouldn't go out of your way to add salt
to that
if i've missed my mark right so in terms
of sorry in terms of pre-hydration
we want to drink that at least a half
body weight in pounds uh body weight in
pounds per ounce in ounces of water per
day
and i adjust the amount based on my
context so my lifestyle what i do for
work humidity temperature
and my heavy sweater my light sweater
etc right
and you use the what system right so
weigh yourself first thing in the
morning
check your hydration and check your
thirst if you miss that
say for example you didn't get enough of
that water in then you want to hit
somewhere in the neighborhood of four to
six hundred milliliters or
you know 15 to 20 ounces a couple of
hours before and then another 5 or 10
ounces
you know 15 or 20 minutes before the
workout
then we want a perihydrate so we want to
drink fluids during the workout again i
said take your body weight in pounds
divide that by 30 and drink that every
15 minutes or so
if that's uncomfortable keep at it
because your gut can improve and it
won't feel that sloshy
after a while then you want to drink
back sweat something between that three
to four
to one sodium to chloride to potassium
ratio with that five to nine percent
glucose and
some fructose solution examples coconut
water with a little bit of salt maybe
add some honey
or an element and then put that in a
dextrose powder something like that
you want to assess your sweat content
either with the the visual thing i said
or buying a patch and experiment with
the aforementioned sweat in other words
try different combinations and cocktails
of drinks
and then post hydration take your body
weight pre and post your workout and
drink 125 percent of that or so
all right as i mentioned if you want to
know more about the physiology more the
science
go check out part one and part two of
the 55-minute series if not though
i think i pretty did a pretty good darn
good job of covering all that in
kind of close to 25 minutes i know i was
so close i was trying to knock it out
but i missed
all right i appreciate your attention i
appreciate all the love and
go get some water
[Music]